http://www.kangan.edu.au/en/privacy-statement

Find a Course
TAFE Courses
Browse For TAFE CoursesInformation Sessions Change of Preference
How to Apply Skills RecognitionStudy Explained
Online Service StandardsFlexible Learning FAQ
Short Courses
Browse for Short CoursesVIC Roads Vehicle TestingHow to Enrol
FAQ
Apprenticeships and Traineeships
School-based apprenticeships and traineeships (SBAT)Pre-apprenticeships
Fees and Policies
Eligibility for Government Subsidised TrainingWays to Pay, Concessions & RefundsKangan Policies
Broadmeadows
Docklands (ACE)
Essendon
Moonee Ponds (Health)
Richmond (Creative Industries)
Facilities
CafeteriaLibrary and Learning CentrePrintroom
RestaurantWireless LAN and Computer Labs
Training Centres
Automotive Centre of ExcellenceIndigenous Education CentreRichards Restaurant
Textile and Fashion Hub
Prospective Students
Our Blog
How to Compare Victorian TAFE Courses6 Reasons to Enrol in a TAFE to University PathwayTAFE to University Pathway - Kayla’s StorySelf-care 101
How to make the most out of self-isolationDavid Salmeron - Teacher at Automotive Centre of ExcellenceJoseph Thompson - Diploma of Automotive TechnologyMeet Jessie Lin – Student of General English
Meet Santiago – Student of General EnglishHow Allied Health Professionals are Helping More People Now Than Ever5 Steps to Break Into the Fashion IndustryYour Guide to Mastering Spoken & Written English
Current Students
Your Unique Student Identifier (USI)USI update formOnline Service Standards
Student Support
Support servicesDiscount and SpecialsAccommodationStudent Email Forwarding
Course CounsellingPersonal CounsellingDisability SupportStudy Support
Indigenous SupportLearning SupportWelfare and Financial SupportEvents
Career Advisors
PublicationsScholarship and Grants
Skills and Job Centre
Reconnect
Employment Centre
Employment TipsRegister With UsUseful Links
Weekly Vacancy List
Pathways to University
Business, Management & LegalCommunity & EducationPathways in Beauty Therapy
Pathways in Community Services, Health and WellbeingPathways to Hospitality, Culinary & BakingPathways to Trades & Sustainability
Apprenticeships and Traineeships
Browse for apprenticeship and traineeship coursesSchool-based apprenticeships and traineeships (SBAT)Pre-apprenticeships
For employers and businessesHow to apply FAQ
Departments
AutomotiveBuilt and Natural EnvironmentsCentre for Competitive OperationsCentre for Fashion and Creative Industries
Centre for Foundation and Language SkillsCentre for Health and Community ServicesCentre for YouthEngineering and Security
Culinary and TourismIndigenous Education CentreInformation Communication Technology
Graduation
Graduation and Awards Ceremony Information
Workplace Training
Training PartnershipsContact Us
Business enterprise centre
Connect industry news
Employment Centre
Contact UsRegister With us
Textile and Fashion Hub
Visa Program 457 Contribution
Training Benchmark ATraining Benchmark B
Courses
For Students
Living in MelbourneStudying at Kangan InstituteELICOSEntry Requirements
Student Support ServicesOther languagesTestimonialsOrientation
GraduationPhoto GalleryPathways PartnersAlumni
For International Agents
How to Become an International Agent with Kangan InstituteMarketing MaterialFrequently Asked Questions
Claiming CommissionImportant Dates
International Business
Pathways To University
Education Agents
You are here :
Home/privacy-statement
Kangan Institute Privacy Statement
Purpose
To confirm Bendigo Kangan Institutes efforts to meet its obligations under State and Federal legislation to manage personal and private information.
Click here to see Privacy Policy
Scope
This policy applies to all employees and contractors responsible for collecting, using, storing or otherwise managing security and privacy of personal information.
References
Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic)
Health Records Act 2001 (Vic)
Privacy Act 1988 (Cth)
Privacy Officer
If you have an enquiry or concern about how the institute handles personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer: privacyofficer@kangan.edu.au
Principles
As a staff community we embrace the following core values as the foundation to guide how we work at Bendigo Kangan Institute:
Respect for people
Initiative
Accountability
Customer Consciousness
Built-In-Quality
Working Together
Innovation
Continuous Improvement
Enterprise Thinking
Policy Statement
Bendigo Kangan Institute is bound by and aims to comply with the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic), the Health Records Act 2001 (Vic) and the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (Privacy Laws). Bendigo Kangan Institute has implemented practices and procedures to ensure compliance with those Privacy Laws.
At Bendigo Kangan Institute we respect the rights of individuals (our employees, contractors, business partners and students) to security, privacy and service and we wish them to have confidence that the personal and health information they supply to the Institute will be stored and used appropriately.
This policy describes the way that Bendigo Kangan Institute collects, holds and discloses personal information and the controls it has imposed to ensure compliance with the Privacy Laws. In this policy the terms "personal Information" and "sensitive information" bear their meanings defined in the Privacy Laws, but in substance, "personal information" refers to information about or related to an identifiable individual, while "sensitive information" is personal information about the relevant individual which is subject to additional controls. It includes details such as ethic origin, political and religious affiliations, sexual preferences, criminal record and union membership.
Collection of information
We will only collect personal information that is relevant to our dealings with the person to whom that personal information relates. We may collect personal information (including sensitive information) about individuals, including employees (part, full time, casual, temporary or contract), students, independent contractors and various representatives of the customers and suppliers we deal with. The kind of information we collect depends on the purpose for which it is collected. In relation to our employees and students we may collect name and home contact details, including addresses, phone numbers and email addresses. We may also collect details of their next of kin for emergency contact purposes. We may be required to collect some sensitive information in relation to students for the purpose of monitoring and reporting on participation in education and our performance as an education provider. For customers' and suppliers' representatives, we typically collect name, telephone and email contact details.
How We Collect Information
Wherever reasonably possible, we collect personal information from the person to whom it relates (you). That is not always possible or appropriate and we do collect and use personal information from publicly available sources and from third parties. Some of the services we provide involve the provision of educational services to employers and in collaboration with other training organisations. In the performance of those services we are frequently provided with personal information which has been collected by an employer or other training provider.
In all situations where we obtain personal information from a third party we are careful to seek confirmation from those providing us with the information that it was acquired in accordance with the requirements of the Privacy Laws, that they are entitled to provide it to us and that they are able to authorise us to use it for the purposes for which they are supplying it.
So far as is reasonably possible we are happy to deal with you anonymously or under a pseudonym, if you prefer. Generally we are happy to provide information about our services without requiring you to provide contact details.
If you do deal with us under a pseudonym, we would of course prefer to know that it is a pseudonym, so as to avoid collecting inaccurate information. Similarly, if you have provided us with your contact details, and those details subsequently change, we would appreciate your informing us of the change so that we can ensure our records are kept up to date.
Use
Bendigo Kangan Institute uses the personal information it collects:
to communicate with and promote its services to students and potential students;
to enable Bendigo Kangan Institute to provide services to the individuals to whom the information relates;
to assess applications (both for enrolment and for employment) where the information relates to an applicant; and
to deal with its customers and suppliers in relation to the provision of its services.
Where Bendigo Kangan Institute has been engaged by your employer to provide educational services to you, or is delivering a course in which you are enrolled in collaboration with another training provider, Bendigo Kangan Institute may share any personal information it obtains from you with your employer or the other training provider to the extent reasonably necessary to deliver its services.
As a training services provider, Bendigo Kangan Institute may be required by the Victorian State Government to collect personal information, including sensitive information, relating to students on behalf of the State Government. In such cases, the collection of such information will be identified as being for the purposes of the State Government and Bendigo Kangan Institute will collect that information as agent of the State Government. Bendigo Kangan will not retain or use such information for its own purposes.
Disclosure
We will not divulge any personal or health information to a third party for any reason other than the primary purpose for which it was collected unless the disclosure is required by law. We may, however, in carrying out that primary purpose, engage third parties to act on our behalf. For example, we may engage information technology suppliers, marketing and advertising agencies, mailing and logistics providers and professional advisors. We may disclose personal information we have collected to these third parties for the purposes of their work and, equally, they may provide us with personal information they have collected from you in the course of providing products or services to us. In all cases where the information was collected by us, or on our behalf by those service providers, it will be stored, accessed and used in accordance with this policy and we will ensure that all service providers we engage comply with this policy.
Where we collect personal information from you as agent on behalf of a third party, we may disclose that personal information to that third party.
If Bendigo Kangan Institute intends to disclose any personal information it collects from you in any other manner than those contemplated above, we will inform you at the time the information is collected.
Bendigo Kangan Institute will not disclose any personal information it collects to any person located outside Australia unless:
we have obtained the consent of the person to whom the information relates to that disclosure;
the recipient of the information is subject to a law or binding scheme, that provides at least a substantially similar level of protection in respect of the use of personal information to that available under Australian law and the person to whom the information relates is directly able to enforce their rights in respect of that protection; or
the disclosure is otherwise in compliance with our obligations under the Privacy Laws.
Data Quality
We will take all reasonable steps to ensure the information that is collected is complete, accurate and current.
Data Security
We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that information is protected from misuse, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. All information not required will be destroyed in accordance with Privacy Laws or as required by other legislation or as required under guidance from the Public Records Office.
Access and Correction
If you wish to obtain a copy of any personal information we hold which relates to you, request that we correct that information, request that we delete that information or make a complaint relating to our collection or use of your personal information, please contact Bendigo Kangan Institute's privacy officer at privacy@bendigokangan.edu.au or by post at: The Privacy Officer, 136 McCrae Street, Bendigo VIC 3550. Please note that we will require you to adequately identify yourself when requesting a copy of your personal information.
In some circumstances, in particular where the volume of information you have requested is substantial or extends beyond solely the personal information of yours that we hold, we may require that you submit your request in the form of an application under the Freedom of Information Act. Our provision of access to information under this policy is in addition to any rights of access you may have under the Freedom of Information Act.
We aim to provide any requested information and respond to any complaint within 30 days. Where you request the correction of any information, we aim to correct our records within 5 days of receiving your written request to do so.
We aim to act reasonably in resolving all complaints, but if you are unsatisfied with the response from Bendigo Kangan Institute, you may wish to address your complaint to either:
Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, GPO Box 5218, Sydney NSW 2001
Email: enquiries@oaic.gov.au
(Responsible for the administration of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth))
Commissioner for Privacy and Data Protection, PO Box 24014, Melbourne VIC 3001
Email: privacy@cpdp.vic.gov.au
(Responsible for the administration of the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic))
Unique identifiers
Sometimes we have to collect unique identifiers such as Centrelink numbers, Tax File Numbers or Health Care Card Numbers. If we do need this information the purposes for collecting these numbers will be explained at the time the information is collected.
We will not use these unique identifiers for any other purposes than those for which they were collected.
If we ascribe a unique identifier to you for our internal use that identifier will not be shared with any other body or person without your consent.
Version Control and Change History
Ver.
The content of this policy originated from Kangan Institute KI Privacy Policy, POL 1.5, version 5
